I wasn't even initiated yet, I'd joined in May of 1971,
Non ero ancora neanche iniziato, ne ho preso parte nel maggio del 1971
[Disciples as Flower Offerings]
[I Discepoli come Offerte di Fiori]
and around June­--July I was in Los Angeles.
e intorno a Giugno-Luglio ero a Los Angeles,
Prabhupād would go for a walk in the morning.
Prabhupād andava a fare una passeggiata al mattino.
When he would come back, around seven o'clock,
Quando tornava, intorno alle sette,
we'd all be waiting with flowers. We'd each have a flower,
noi tutti lo aspettavamo con dei fiori, ciascuno di noi aveva un fiore,
and Prabhupād would come and we'd hand him a flower,
e Prabhupād arrivava e noi gli porgevamo un fiore,
and he'd accept the flower and then he'd give you a flower.
ed egli accettava il fiore e poi dava a te un fiore.
We didn't know so much about protocol or things, but that was nice.
Non conoscevamo molto il protocollo o cose del genere, ma era bello.
Hand him a flower, he'd accept your flower, and then give you a flower.
Porgevi a lui un fiore, accettava il tuo fiore, e poi dava a te un fiore.
And sometimes, Guru Mahārāj, Gurudev,
E qualche volta, Guru Mahārāj, Gurudev,
they considered that really the disciples,
consideravano davvero che i discepoli
they shall be considered like flowers;
dovessero essere considerati come fiori;
like flower offerings to the lotus feet of Kṛṣṇa.
come offerte di fiori ai piedi di loto di Kṛṣṇa.
Gurudev, I remember, once on his veranda in Kolkata,
Gurudev, mi ricordo, una volta nella sua veranda a Calcutta,
so many devotees were coming, maybe for the annual festival of some sort,
molti devoti stavano venendo, forse per un qualche festival annuale,
and his veranda was now filled with so many,
e la sua veranda era occupata da moltissimi devoti,
and he would look out and see in that small space eighty or a hundred people.
ed egli guardava fuori e vedeva in quel piccolo spazio ottanta o cento persone.
He was overwhelmed, they were expressing so much appreciation for him,
Ne era sopraffatto, essi stavano esprimendo tanto apprezzamento per Lui
but he was saying, on this particular occasion,
ma egli diceva, in questa particolare occasione,
"You're all gifts of Śrila Guru Mahārāj",
"Voi siete tutti doni di Śrila Guru Mahārāj”,
and that stuck— peeked my remembrance.
e questo mi ha fatto scavare nei miei ricordi.
"Oh, we heard from Srila Prabhupād so many years ago
"Oh, avevamo sentito da Srila Prabhupād tanti anni fà
that a maha-bhagavata guru doesn't see anyone as a disciple".
che un maha-bhagavata Guru non vede nessuno come un discepolo,
But, and later confirmed by Guru Mahārāj,
ma, e fù poi confermato da Guru Maharaj,
rather sees them as vaibhav, or extensions of his own guru.
piuttosto li vede come vaibhav o estensioni del proprio Guru.